

Muhammad Suhail Bhatti

0334 3078719 | Email: sbhatti_2k@hotmail.com

C-7-12 Eden Value Homes, Thokar Niaz Baig, Multan Road, Lahore

DOB: Jan 11, 1980 Domicile: Lahore RELIGION: Islam Gender: Male

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Highly motivated IT professional with a passion for Information Technology having experience in computer, networking. Highly familiar with networking, OS, and monitoring software and office administration.

SKILLS \bigcirc

- Network / System Administration
- Network monitoring
- ISO 27001
- Firewall management,
- Inventory management
- Virtualization
- Written and oral communication

WORK HISTORY

Network Administrator

01/2019 to 11/2019

Orion Engineering

Lahore

Oversee and manage the team responsible for the campus wired/wireless networks, IT infrastructure, network level security architecture, and Internet/WAN connectivity.

Develop departmental standard operating procedures.

Performs limited advanced technical duties in support of large or multiple project teams' projects and operations. Serves as a technical resource for other staff members.

Conducted security audits to identify vulnerabilities in computers and networks.

Monitored usage of data files and regulated access to protected secure information.

Managing data and ensured confidentiality according to information security Plan.

ASST. IT MANAGER

09/2011 to 11/2018

The Urban Unit | Planning & Development Govt. of Punjab, Lahore

- Monitored usage of data files and regulated access to protected secure information.
- Managing data and ensured confidentiality according to information security Plan.
- Perform configuration management for entire network and installed hardware, software, windows servers and other operating system to maintain optimal performance for system.

- Conducted security audits to identify vulnerabilities in computers and networks.
- Prepare designs and documentation of new networks, deploy network test plans, technical operations regarding IT network integration and configuration, propose modifications in existing networks
- Designed IT support strategy that clearly defined workflow between external clients, application teams, and infrastructure team.
- Research, investigate and evaluate current networking activities and operational procedures to identify flaws, errors and abnormalities and suggest improvements and upgrades to meet security requirements
- Updated and installed appropriate security patches/updates to eliminate hacking ability as well as dissolve security vulnerabilities.
- Diagnosing hardware and software issues, perform troubleshooting and maintenance of computer systems, Server and network hardware to ensure integrity and consistency in network operations.
- Configuring Router, Firewall, manageable switches L2, L3 and Load Balance.
- Collaborated with internal and external departments to ensure smooth work flow and efficient organization operations.
- Management and maintenance of Network Printer, Plotter, Book eye Scanner, Flatbed Scanner (A4 size to A0 size)
- Monitoring and maintaining flow of network traffic including web filtering by using monitoring software.
- Provided professional assistance in developing operation activities including CCTV Surveillance, Storage, Servers, Public Address System and UPS for IT Component of Metro Bus System Project, Lahore
- Supervise IT team for daily IT tasks and supervise IT store team for inventory management system (IMS) and asset tagging assignments.
- Management of NAS, SAN storages
- Installation of Server 2008, 2012 and Windows OS 7,8 10
- Provide IT Support to staff regarding OS and related software like MS Office suit, antivirus client, ARC GIS 10.3, Adobe Photoshop suit and many other software as per demand.
- Responsible for network, system and data availability and integrity through maintenance and upgrades for computer hardware and network equipment.
- Configuring networking equipment (AP, Router, printer, Scanner, DVR, NAS)
- Conduct meeting on video conference equipment and Skype meeting.
- Inspection of IT equipment procured by Procurement department.
- Provided IT support for seminar, workshop and training conducted by department.
- Maintain IT store with respect of issuance and receiving.

CUSTOMER SUPPORT EXECUTIVE (PART TIME)

12/2007 to 07/2009

Hipxpert LTd. | London, UK

- Assist sales team to manage quotations, process orders and claims.
- Giving support to client's queries over the phone, coordinate with surveyor and technicians regarding client complaints.

WORK HISTORY

ASSISTANT NETWORK ADMINISTRATOR

02/2003 to 09/2004

Venus Communications | Karachi

- Installing, Troubleshooting and Managing Servers (MS 2003 Server, MS Server ISA)
- Manage Network Users, Updating user policy regarding security Issues.
- Installation of User workstation OS and necessary software's.
- Designing, deploying and maintaining user databases and spreadsheets logs.
- Managing technical reports.
- Control Access Privileges, Update Security patches
- Administration of Routers, Firewalls and Switches
- Remotely managed different users systems

EDUCATION \bigcirc

Master of Science | Information System July, 2009 Sheffield Hallam University (SHU), Sheffield - United Kingdom

Bachelor of Engineering | Computer Systems 1999- 2003

NED University of Engineering & Technology, Karachi - Pakistan

TRAINING/ OCERTIFICATION

- BSi- ISMS Auditor/Lead Auditor (MSc. Module attended)
- CCNA (MSc. Module attended)
- MCSE (Microsoft Certified Solution Expert) Server Infrastructure Certified (2014)
- Assessing and Auditing Wireless Networks | SANS , (GIAC)
 Certified (2008-2012)
- Pakistan Engineering Council (PEC) Registered Engineer, Since 2010

REFERENCE

Will be provide on request.